raf.mod.uk 2018-08-21

# Privacy | Royal Air Force

We collect certain information or data about you when you use our site. This includes your IP address, details of which version of a web browser you used and information on how you use the site. We do this by using cookies and page tagging techniques.

This helps us to improve the site by monitoring how you use it. We can’t personally identify you using this data.

### Where your data is stored

We store your data on our secure servers. It may be viewed by our staff or suppliers. By submitting any of your personal data (for instance by filling in a form), you agree to this.

### Keeping your data secure

Transmitting information over the internet is generally not completely secure, and we can’t guarantee the security of your data. Any data you transmit is at your own risk. We have procedures and security features in place to try and keep your data secure once we receive it. We won’t share your information with any other organisations for marketing, market research or commercial purposes, and we don’t pass on your details to other websites.

### Disclosing your information

We may pass on your personal information if we have a legal obligation to do so, or if we have to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements.

### Links to other websites

This website may contain links to and from other websites. This privacy policy only applies to this website, and doesn’t cover other services or sites that we link to. If you go to another website from this one, we advise you to read the privacy policy on that website to find out what it does with your information.

### Cookies

Small files (known as ‘cookies’) are put onto your computer to collect information about how you browse the site.

Cookies are used to:

  * measure how you use the website so it can be updated and improved based on your needs
  * remember the notifications you’ve seen so that we don’t show them to you again

These cookies aren’t used to identify you personally.

You’ll normally see a message on the site before we store a cookie on your computer.

Find out more about [how to manage cookies](https://www.aboutcookies.org/).

### How cookies are used on the RAF website

#### Measuring website usage (Google Analytics)

We use Google Analytics software to collect information about how you use the RAF website. We do this to help make sure the site is meeting the needs of its users and to help us make improvements.

Google Analytics stores information about:

  * the pages you visit on the RAF website
  * how long you spend on each page
  * how you got to the site
  * what you click on while you’re visiting the site

We don’t collect or store your personal information (eg your name or address) so this information can’t be used to identify who you are.

We don’t allow Google to use or share our analytics data.

Google Analytics sets the following cookies:

##### Universal Analytics and Google Tag Manager

Name: _ga  
Purpose: This helps us count how many people visit the RAF website by tracking if you’ve visited before  
Expires: 2 years

Name: _gat  
Purpose: Used to manage the rate at which page view requests are made  
Expires: 10 minutes

Name: _gat_UA-XXXXXXXXX  
Purpose: Used by Google Tag Manager to link to GA account  
Expires: When you close your browser

Name: _gid  
Purpose: Used by Google Tag Manager to track if you’ve visited before  
Expires: When you close your browser

You can [opt out of Google Analytics cookies](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

##### Session tracking

Name: X-Mapping-fjhppofk  
Purpose: Provides session tracking across a load balancing server  
Expires: When you close your browser

Name: cfid  
Purpose: Provides session tracking within the application server  
Expires: When you close your browser

Name: cftoken  
Purpose: Provides session tracking within the application server  
Expires: When you close your browser
